flybuys.co.nz 2016-10-21

# FlyBuys: Learn / Privacy statement

[Home](https://www.flybuys.co.nz/) > Learn > Privacy statement

####  Overview

Loyalty New Zealand Limited, operator of the Fly Buys programme in New Zealand, respects the privacy of your personal information in our care and we adhere to strict guidelines as set out in this Privacy Statement.

We describe below:

  * the types of personal information we collect through the Fly Buys programme and how we collect it;
  * how we hold that personal information;
  * how and for what purposes we use that personal information;
  * who we share that personal information with and for what purposes; and
  * the data we collect from use of our digital services, including the Fly Buys website (www.flybuys.co.nz), social media channels and the Fly Buys mobile app.

This Privacy Statement may be updated from time to time.

You accept the terms and conditions of the Fly Buys programme, including this Privacy Statement, by continuing to use your Fly Buys membership card.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact our Privacy Officer using the contact details included at the end of the statement.

####  What types of personal information do we collect and how do we collect it?

The types of personal information we collect and hold include:

  * name, contact details such as address and telephone number, age and gender details. We collect this information through the form you complete to join the Fly Buys programme or through forms you may submit in relation to a Fly Buys promotion;
  * details of your transactions with businesses that offer Fly Buys points ( **Fly Buys Partners** ), such as the date you shopped, how much you spent, your payment method and what you have bought. We collect this information as a result of you providing your Fly Buys membership card/membership card number to a Fly Buys Partner when making a purchase in store or online;
  * Fly Buys reward redemption details, such as the reward you redeemed Fly Buys points for and the date of your redemption;
  * records of your communications and interactions with us in relation to the Fly Buys programme, such as when you communicate with the Fly Buys Service Centre via phone or email; and
  * details of the communication preferences you have given us, such as whether you are opted in to receive Fly Buys promotional emails.

Without this personal information we may not be able to provide certain benefits and services to you, such as:

  * allocating to you Fly Buys points you have earned;
  * enabling you to redeem points for rewards;
  * keeping your Fly Buys programme membership details updated and secure;
  * sending you offers that may be of interest to you; and
  * providing you with information about your Fly Buys membership.

When you visit the Fly Buys website or use the Fly Buys mobile application we may collect information using technology which is not apparent to you (such as “cookies”). Please see the section below on data collected in relation to digital services for more information about our use of this technology.

####  How and for what purposes do we use personal information?

We use your contact details, information about your shopping with Fly Buys Partners and other types of information about you held by us (as described above) to promote to you products and services, provided by Fly Buys, Fly Buys Partners and other businesses that are relevant to you and that we think you may want.

We may use such information about you to provide marketing communications and targeted advertising to you by email, mail and/or telephone.

You can opt out of receiving offers from us anytime – either specific offers, offers from a particular business or from one particular channel (e.g. email or telephone) altogether.

There are a number of ways you can opt out.

  * if you have been emailed an offer, you can click to unsubscribe via that email;
  * by logging into the Fly Buys website, going to My Account, selecting communications options and checking your preferences;
  * by calling us on 0800 FLY BUYS (Monday to Friday from 8am – 6pm); or
  * by writing to the Fly Buys Service Centre, PO Box 68679, Newton, Auckland (no stamp required).

We may use your contact details, information about your shopping with Fly Buys Partners and other types of information about you that we hold (as described above):

  * to facilitate the delivery of rewards requested by you;
  * to verify your identity (e.g. if you seek access to services or information via the Fly Buys website or a call to the Fly Buys Service Centre);
  * to conduct product and market research for the Fly Buys programme, Fly Buys Partners and other businesses not participating in Fly Buys;
  * to carry out data analytics services for the purpose of providing insights and aggregated data (i.e. data that cannot be linked to an individual) to Fly Buys Partners and other organisations;
  * to maintain and update our Fly Buys membership records; and
  * to deal with enquiries from you.

####  With whom and for what purposes do we share personal information?

To operate the Fly Buys programme, we share personal information with some trusted providers of Fly Buys related services, including the operator of the Fly Buys Service Centre, mail-houses, our email deployment company, reward suppliers and providers of data analysis, data augmentation or data washing services in connection with Fly Buys marketing campaigns.

We may share your personal information with a provider of Fly Buys related services that is located in a country other than New Zealand, where we have made a business decision to use a trusted overseas based service provider that is in the business of providing data storage and/or data processing services (for example, the service provider that hosts our Fly Buys email marketing platform).

We ensure that any time we share personal information with Fly Buys service providers we do so securely and we take steps to ensure that all our service providers with whom we share personal information agree to protect the privacy and security of your personal information, destroy that data when it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was supplied to them and use that data only for the purposes for which it is disclosed.

From time to time we may share your personal information with a Fly Buys Partner (or its agent) if:

  * we consider on reasonable grounds that you have consented to that disclosure;
  * we consider on reasonable grounds that that disclosure is necessary to enable the recording of point(s) in relation to a transaction with a Fly Buys Partner;
  * you are a prize winner in a competition or promotion run by or on behalf of that Fly Buys Partner and the information is disclosed for the sole purpose of enabling notification to you that you are the prize winner and/or making arrangements for receipt of the prize; or
  * we consider on reasonable grounds that you may have been involved in fraudulent activities in relation to that Fly Buys Partner.

We may also share your Fly Buys membership card number with a Fly Buys Partner with whom you have an exisiting customer account, to link the accounts together so you can collect points for spend on that account and receive other benefits from that partner.

Personal information that relates to a transaction with a Fly Buys Partner in which a Fly Buys enabled Airpoints membership card has been used by an Airpoints member may be supplied by us to Air New Zealand in accordance with the consents given by Airpoints members under the Airpoints Terms and Conditions.

From time to time we may share your personal information in other circumstances where we are specifically allowed to under the Privacy Act 1993 (for example, in cases where the Police ask us for information to assist with its investigation of an alleged criminal offence).

####  How do we hold personal information?

We take data security very seriously. We have in place rigorous data security policies and practices aimed at mitigating the risks of unauthorised access to, and loss, misuse or wrongful alteration of, personal information held by us.

We take measures to destroy or anonymise personal information held by us if we no longer need to use it for any lawful purpose.

We are dedicated to keeping your Fly Buys membership details safe and secure from scams and fraud. If you are ever in any doubt about the authenticity of any communications that are or seem to be from Fly Buys please immediately email us at [contactus@flybuys.co.nz](mailto:contactus@flybuys.co.nz) and include a copy of the email in question.

####  Data collected in relation to digital services

We provide information and services relating to the Fly Buys programme through a range of digital and online services, including the Fly Buys website, social media channels like Facebook, and the Fly Buys app.

Information is collected via your use of the Fly Buys website, through cookies. Cookies are small data files that your browser stores on your computer when you visit certain websites. The cookies on the Fly Buys website allow us to collect information which we use to help us remember the information you enter. This means that as you use the Fly Buys website we can relay any information you entered earlier back to you at a later time. It is possible to disable the acceptance of such cookies from your web browser. However, doing so may restrict your ability to use some of the pages on the Fly Buys website.

We also promote Fly Buys products and services using third party vendors, such as Google Remarketing, as a method of targeting our advertising based on how you interact with the Fly Buys website. Both Fly Buys and these vendors may use cookies to help offer you online ads that are more specifically tailored to you when you visit other websites. These cookies contain no personally identifiable information, they cannot damage files, nor can they read information from the hard drive of a computer. You do not need to accept these cookies, however, and can find more information about opting out by visiting the [Google cookies opt out page](https://www.google.co.nz/intl/en/policies/technologies/ads/).

Our systems record a variety of information in relation to interactions with the Fly Buys website and the Fly Buys app. This can include information about software versions used, device types, device identifiers (like IP address), location data (where available and not disabled by the user), dates, times, file metadata, referring website, data entered, and user activity such as links clicked.

From time to time we may use your data to target you through social media channels, like Facebook. In this case, we match encrypted (hashed) email addresses with encrypted Facebook data to identify a match in a secure environment. The hashed data is deleted as soon as the match is complete and never kept or used by Facebook or shared with any third party.

Some information we collect in relation to our digital services is not related to an individual. In many cases, the information relates only to a device or is of an aggregated or statistical nature, and we will have no way of knowing the identity of the user. In other cases, we may associate information about your use of our digital services over time with your personal information, for example, when on any occasion you have logged in, followed a link sent to you by email, or we have otherwise been able to identify you.

Our online services may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of those sites and recommend that you review their privacy policies.

####  Procedures for access, correction, and feedback

If you wish to access or correct any information we hold about you or have any feedback or concerns about privacy, please contact us as set out below. Where you seek a response from us, we will let you know who will be handling your matter and when you can expect a full response. In the case of access and correction requests, please provide as much detail as you can about the particular information you seek in order to help us retrieve it. Where we decide not to make a requested correction and you disagree, you may ask us to make a note of your requested correction with the information.

**Phone:** 0800 FLY BUYS ([0800 359 2897](tel:0800 359 2897)), Mon – Fri, 8am – 6pm (excluding public holidays)

**Post:** Fly Buys Service Centre, PO Box 68679, Newton, Auckland
